La-Keisha M. Towner

Software Developer

■LTowner622@gmail.com LMTowner.com 646-338-5494 Greater New York Area

SUMMARY

I currently working at a Mobile development company who platform is catered to improving communication in Enterprise companies. We make personalized iOS and Android applications for each company we cater to as well as a customized web application.

My official title at APPrise Mobile is a Customer Support Engineer, where I am responsible for fixing any and all of the Customer facing issues. When I am not fixing customer bugs, I am building new features for our platform to enhance their User Experience. I work primarily with Javascript, utilizing libraries like React and React Native, for the front-end development, and Node.js with Express.js for server implementations for building APIs, and MongoDB, Redis, and Postgresql for storage.

EDUCATION

University at Buffalo

BS Chemistry 2011

CUNY New York City College of Technology

Computer Systems Networking and Telecommunications 2016

EMPLOYMENT

APPrise Mobile, Software Engineer, New York, NY

Sept. 2017 - Current

Build new features for mobile phones such as Android & iOS

Wrote scripts to guery our database for complex data gueries to build reports and manipulate data

Fix reported bugs for more than 100 companies' web platform as well as on their native mobile application

Built an internal desktop application utilizing Electron is for the Client Sucess to better manage multiple company accounts

Created custom analytics tracking utilizing Mix Panel for companies' to gauge how their employees are utilizing their web and mobile platform

Dev Bootcamp, Mentor, New York, NY

July 2017 - Dec. 2017

Provided feedback to all students based on their web development challenges Gave academic support to over 30 students with their daily projects and challenges Conducted live coding sessions in Ruby, Ruby on Rails & various Javascript Libraries.

NYC Office Suites, Client Services Manager, New York, NY

Aug. 2011 - Dec. 2016

Provided technical support to over 150 clientele including desktop help remotely.

Maintaining and configuring routers, switches and VLANs.

Introduced and trained all new team members to operating systems and standard network configurations.

Managed day to day activity for 44,000 square foot serviced office.

SKILLS

DATABASES: SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

CLIENT-SIDE: Javascript, React, Ajax, HTML, Redux, React Native, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, JQuery

 $\textbf{SERVER-SIDE:} \ \mathsf{APIS,} \ \mathsf{Node.js,} \ \mathsf{Express.js,} \ \mathsf{Ruby,} \ \mathsf{Ruby} \ \mathsf{on} \ \mathsf{Rails,} \ \mathsf{GraphQL}$

TEAM BUILDING: Agile Methodoligies, Git Flow UNIT TESTING: Mocha, Chai

INFRASTRUCTURE: AWS, Elastic Beanstalk, Docker

PROJECTS

DJ-Mood April 2017

An application that takes a short, 3-second video of the user's face, analyzes the emotions it is displaying and uses those emotions to generate a playlist from Spotify. Kairo's API is used to analyze emotion from the user's face.

Spotify's API is used to compile a playlist in the user's personal Spotify Account. Technologies used were MongoDB, Express, NodeJS & Pug Templating.

Pistachios

Pistachios is a social networking site that allows users to connect with other users to post stories and read other's thoughts Built using Ruby on Rails 5.0 PostgreSQL for database

What Do you Want to Eat Tonight

June 2017

Application was designed to take the guesswork out of planning a dinner amongst friends

Front-end was build using React Native, Back-end was built using Loopback framework for Node along with MongoDB for storage

Yelp API was used for restaurant queries

Won 'Best implementation of Loopback' at MobileMonday's Hackathon

AWARDS

Best implementation of Loopback, MobileMondays Hackathon Won the contest for setting up LoopBack in my project.

LoopBack is a scaffolding tool to set an web API using Express.is

June 2017

May 2017